I was sitting here asking my
friends when we start this
noise rim
in November 2010, we started this makeup 12 years
ago
and
from my ideas and why it was necessary to teach this
lavra because it will take
20 years and for me
if I get an injection of nam rim
every six months it keeps me
on the path
[music]
they are the same age, it will probably
work and it seems very
comfortable for me this lam rim
lasted 30 years from my teacher and
it was very comfortable
that it was several times a year and it
supported me on the path I
don’t know if this happened to you or not with
me it was that I sat down to meditate
went through preliminary practices
then did not know what to meditate about and
sometimes I just forgot I had
some specific
object for meditation when you can
just
do nam rim if you have an injection of
this nam rim several times a year, I
think this is a wonderful thing and you
always have something you
need to meditate on
such a thing will come this time in
this session when he will say such
strange things
that  He says that we are afraid of the purpose of
meditation, Lam-Rim, more than death.
I mean, what does he want to say? He
said we
like all these attractive
Mahamudra meditations, focus on emptiness,
we like to go
deeper, like these deeper meditation books,
and about Quarter Smith,
for example, a book, and then someone
who says so,
meditation time needs to stop
for translation, dark, deep exhale, need to
slow down a little, say we have a
tendency, he says, I like to
focus on these sounds in
meditations, which, for example, immediately on
sex, but every few months,
come back to us, remorse, where do you
find in this,
and
you will have such a
constant flow. It
prevented us from continuing for another ten years, and
so come back to this. We
try
this, always take you beyond the earth, and it will always give
you some orientation for your whole
life. You have a friend, a
spiritual structure for your whole life, and I
really encourage you
to follow the scrap repair at least twice a
year. I also teach a special program,
for example, there, medicine, and the second leg is a
wife, and we will continue to do this.
I will still insist on returning to the
rubbish rimu students, we want more.
We want more emptiness, the Congress of Buddha
Medicine, and I will force them to return
their trash to Rome a couple of times a year,
so here we go, a
recording of the teachings on the steps on the path to
enlightenment,
which I have already done everything according to the race of
Rinpoche, he taught,
he was the teacher of my teacher and the teachers of
my teacher's teacher, so
my teacher's teacher was under Jungle in the century,
who was the junior teacher of His
Holiness the Dalai Lama,
and he was also the greatest teacher of
his time, his teacher was also the
greatest teacher of his time, three
Changlin Kache,
I don't remember how much time is not said,
I think
he was about twenty,
and under John Glen Pache, he made a transcript.
This is the teaching
that lasted about 20 years, and
he
perfected this recording for a very long time, and he
perfected Tibetan, and
since Tibetan is now practically
lost, this is probably the greatest
book of the tapir, I was written in
Tibetan, Zinc Po was, of course, a great
master, but linguistically, this book, I
think, is the greatest example of
anything
Someone once asked me what the
greatest book in Tibetan was written and I
would say this book and,
for example, I am addicted to books, my wife
accuses me
of this, she says that between me and my
books, I'm not sure what you will choose and
I have approximately several
thousand favorite books in Teletsky and this is the
greatest when we started 12 per
vote,
I first taught the last two to the
last sections of Shaman and Defarge with a
member, so we go back first we
studied converting then emptiness and
then we started over and
why did she do it this way because
classically it
is supposed to meditate on these topics
when you go through Lam Rim, that is, it
should be days, that is, based on experience,
teaching based on experience, you study the
topic, then you go to the best
slab
retreat center in the universe, Daimon and Yang, and it
is assumed that you meditate,
you go to the subject cabin and
meditate.
We felt that when we were
preparing this retreat a few months ago, it
looked like the world is not
ready yet.  Say goodbye to the virus, but I thought
I think that two days ago in our state we will
complete all
restrictions.
A couple of days ago, I think that we are
returning to normal life. In this
regard,
when is our next retreat in October,
so we will be working again.
You can come if you have to
sit in quarantine.
You are still welcome. There will be a longer
retreat. Then I think all our
employees. We all want to open again in
the fall. We
made a hat and watashi. But then we
returned to the beginning of
normal. And
there is such an interesting thing about this
during which is the presentation of all the
steps on the path to enlightenment. The
part about meditation
is that the part about meditation and emptiness is
quite short. And I think the reason is
that in the
center of all their two thousand pages of the
great
big book of steps on the path to enlightenment,
half is covered in meditation and
meditation on emptiness. So I thought it would be
great to conduct a small
meditation on emptiness from this section,
then
do the
entire lam rim. And because then we will
return again at an hour of incopy and more
lectures, we will do this, and therefore this is our
plan, we are going according to plan.
80 percent we have probably already done
I think in
eight years we will be able to finish the main
book and then go back to that
drop and it will be a lot
it will be
220 in the country of
the hoof itself 440 and we
analyze approximately 8 pages per session that is
50 sessions ha ha something like that
so pray for our long life
and
so this is the first this is the first lesson and team
I need at what time to
stop
[music]
okay we will do this later
I thought the
first lesson it would be good for us to
remember where we are because for
example between sessions I forget everything
we talked about I assume that you are
also in the same situation so that's where we
are there are three commands large sections by someone that is these
people of lower middle and
higher abilities and the
deterioration of the
teaching for people of lower abilities in
general is aimed at not getting down the
neck of measure
in the world of hell and
animals and we completed this part the second
part and
not to
remain in samsara that is even
human birth or the birth of gods
well full of suffering these sufferings are
inevitable you do not have to have  It's not
necessary that there be a war,
midi, they kill themselves beautifully,
because the body kills itself, and you
will grow old and settle into parts, this is
very cool,
I spent the last two days and I am healthy and
they are and
this is just such a routine
repair, routine maintenance because I really
take care of myself, I go to the doctors twice a
year, I don't do everything even if you
carry out routine repairs on time, corner
exercises, I take good
care of this, I think about what I eat
and still everything disintegrates, everything is destroyed
and this is such
suffering, the middle part of your rim is to
kill is a free makes you suffer
because inevitably you can
exercise, you can hear well, you
can go to the doctors so that
they periodically conduct medical examinations,
but still you will all disintegrate,
therefore we have reached the barrel
now
3 sections and this means that I would like to
meet directly with all living
beings of this universe and I would like to
take a vow that I will serve them and over
time I would like to learn how to
help them, how to teach them
this lam rim to get rid of this
type of body and such an existence, I would like
to do this and this is such a great
motivation you need to return to it periodically
and
real experience will scream and if you
are an Aria, such that you actually
meet with every creature in
the universe even before you
achieve enlightenment directly and you will have
a few minutes with them and you
accept you promise to help them and this is
very
touching because all the fish, all the
birds,
probably everyone, even viruses, you meet with them all
and create this serious
strong connection you create a connection with
them you promise this is a wonderful experience if you
distance yourself and the personal thing that you
do with this lagrima of your life you
can’t even imagine how this will
change your life our motivation
feeling about yourself feeling about
what you need to do in this
world if you have this experience and
I call this experience
driven by the planets because the planets are
infinite and the creatures are
theoretically infinite and even if they come
from you you can still visit them all
meet with everyone and
return and you do this in
fact changes your whole life into a blue game
and then you really can’t
and you can already feel very sad  There can be
bad days,
for example, maybe bad coffee,
maybe columns and coffee, by the way, it's
cold for me. You can have bad days, you
can be sad, but in fact, it ca
n't be really terrible because
you had this experience and I highly
recommend
getting this experience and the teaching this time
is just about how to do it, that is, it just so
happened that you came for
serious moments. These sessions are how long is
eight days, something like that,
7 days. It's all aimed at
getting this experience. How to launch this
experience. Wouldn't
it be wonderfully developed? Wouldn't it be the
best thing that
ever happened to you? I think there's
nothing better than
getting this experience except leading. We comprehended it
directly, but you can get
this experience almost simultaneously.
So, the foundation of the topic is, we have the task of
getting this direct experience of bodhichitta. You
may have had other experiences of bodhichitta
before, but nothing more. Such intellectual ones are
not
real and we call it
reed bodhichitta. We
call them approximate, that is, you
chew the peel but not the center.
So, I
will begin now to combine this
great sex.  Lam Rim section of
which we are and I don't worry
translators, I'm slowing down a little about the
steps on the path for those people who
choose to work for everyone.
We went through a section where we said
that the only way to enter this
level
is to obtain bataki bodhichitta and we
talked about distinguishing what this
means,
no, this is a special advantage, cool
things that will happen to you if
you happen and
then we have a section on how to
get it, that is, this is a
typical
thing for sale, advertising first they
tell you some kind of cool car they
are trying to sell
recently we
bought a car for Veronica I'm doing well everything has
changed before they didn't kiss you at 6 so that
you could buy a
car and now they say well, do you need a
new car? Forget about a new car, I'll
call you if we have some kind of
car and
in my world it's almost
unbelievable to see because
before the only people who were lying
around were car sellers
here we also advertise first we
say such a cool car we tell
you you can jump from planet to
planet and then we tell you how to
get this car
maybe we will deliver it to you
March 31st, maybe in two weeks, maybe
much longer, a
very strange color, we were promised this
car, miracles, faithful, the only one in
all of northern Arizona, and then once
you get this experience and
you devote yourself to taking care
of these beings
you
met, I don’t know why, but that’s how it
happens when you meet them, you kind of make a
contract, don’t worry,
I’ll take care of you, and so you
keep your part of this
agreement, and these are the 6 perfections, we’ll
talk about them later, and in fact, I’m
not twisting it yet, in the same way,
get for calling this, and
by the way, bodhichitta is translated as
enlightened mind, this is a bad translation,
it just means that this is the desire to
receive enlightenment, to achieve
enlightenment for the sake of all living beings, this does
not mean that you are already enlightened,
you
promise to achieve enlightenment, so
this is not enlightenment itself, so the first
part is an advertisement, and I think that we
will go through this section
just to give an overview, we will devote a
few minutes to this, and
here is the famous poem about the
cool things that will happen to
you if you receive bodhichitta
[music]
here is a famous famous famous
advertisement for your new car and
[music]
so the first picture team if you can
you will be loved and protected we will have
150 pictures we call them
eat and the idea picture image
I
give you these pictures as a self-
testing mechanism between today and
tomorrow you should be able to
look
I think today there will be 8 to 10 pictures I
want you to
test yourself
you need to remember these pictures if you
remember what these pictures are about then you
remembered and
you need to review them again if the
pictures are until tomorrow so
let's look here again
this is the first advertised benefit of
bodhicitta is that you will be loved and
protected by all enlightened beings
I was walking but I am you are
already protected protection I am already protected and
loved by enlightened beings before but they
will then protect in a special way
after you promise that then your
mom and dad all the Buddhas of the universe of course
they have equal sleep I love all
beings of the universe but you will be given a
special
attitude like a child who helps
the family they will feel
especially  close to you is the first and
there are other beings and they also
mention
spirits, especially powerful ones and even
people, they will be interested in
helping you, they will be attracted to
help you achieve your goals, they
will not even know why they will be
raging about something about
you, by the way, I
took a shower today, but they will be able to smell
that there is something cool there and there are
people who can
sense
what you are going to do, not exactly, they do not
know directly, they do not know what they are
doing, they meet you in the store
and they have some kind of feeling about
you and they serve you, they help you
do things that will help all people and
you feel very protected and you
will feel that you are kind of
nourished by these people because they can
smell your absolute goals, they want to
help you, this is a very cool experience
because people constantly help
you get things and do what you
have planned to do, you throw them
some ideas about projects, this is
very strange because they can
smell what is happening, this is a wonderful
feeling that you are supported, this is the
first point of
advertising, in general, you will receive a
lot of help from the universe,
even if people around you do not really know
what is happening, even people  whom
you have never met will take care
of you, they will protect you from
negative events and bad people, bad
experiences, there will be people who will constantly
protect you and
make sure that nothing bad
happens to you, and while you are engaged in
this mission to
help all living beings, you will
attract support and protection simply
automatically, and your life becomes
quite cool, and the
second picture is here,
and in November,
I found this photo
in
105 photos,
I pay him $ 150 a month
because I like their pictures, always
positive, always friendly, and so the
second advantage of
acquiring headbands is that you are
just
constantly happy, this does not mean that
you do not grumble, if, for example, you do
not have to wake up too early, you
can still grumble in return, mountain
early in the morning, but overall,
you
feel really
happy,
and you notice this, that is, your friends
[music],
they complain, I had a bad day, but
you still, yes, I know, and sometimes they get very
angry at you, why are you in a
good mood all the time, I don’t have one, but overall,
your life will be blessed, and you
will
feel deeply  happy in a
good mood constantly even if
there are things with which something is wrong,
for example,
in the Torah I didn’t catch something wrong
happening and also physically
you
feel that your body is healthy, I am
strong
enough in good condition in 70
years
in general and you will feel good
this is a side effect of bodhichitta this is not the
main goal of course
but it happens and you notice it
okay so now you have two
pictures don’t forget the collision
you can test yourself and you can
use these pictures for your
meditation every day that is when you
return home after this lesson
illuminate
unless of course if you are not
our employee then you need to
work and so in general take a
nap and then do the meditation and
during meditation
I
also like to write down the
names of the pictures and you can go for a
long walk around diamond man man
finds a good place to [ __ ]
what this book was about this picture of this young
lady who was smiling and
test yourself and then the teaching
will stay with you and if not, in the end you will
not be able to remember anything and so 3 2
3 picture 3 apparently
why I have it here  4
times you feel you are always happy
I like this you can't be harmed
ready
I like this picture
you have all sorts of problems in life
and you just go opponent and
this is the third group of
advantages
this is an advertisement for bodhichitta yes of
course there will be problems around you there
will be
wars and viruses and there
will be economic problems and
somehow you will not get into all this
you will just
go along
this is that
you will have to for problems the
right time in the wrong place that
is you have a problem friends of
friends have problems and you feel
guilty because you don't have
these problems and
you feel
sometimes for example I feel guilty that I don't have
big problems well because of
this motivation problems will generally
bypass you
for example in the end of course I got
sick coffee I'll hand in right before the books of
us the last session of mixed nuts and
I was just in despair because
I didn't have
time to prepare 60 lessons I
was just in despair then I also got Jacob and
I had three blissful days in bed
and
Veronica has to ask what
you are working on 12 hours a day and  I'm saying I'm
preparing a mix over because this
Collins only happened during my
three very relaxed days in
bed with my computer on my
stomach,
so I prepared all these classes,
so even if you have problems,
in fact, these are not such big
problems, it's explained, and this is another
advantage of this bodhichitta, that is,
problems happen to
people, people die
from coffee, yes, for example, you
enjoy being ready while preparing for the class,
so in fact, nothing so
bad happens in life, you understand,
okay, the next picture
I saw this picture and I thought it was a
good picture,
you will achieve all your goals, so whatever you
do will work, I think before that
you will try to
do projects, they will not
really work, or someone
will paint them, these things, or they will be
postponed, and will not happen, and if you do
not acquire bodhichitta, then
if you acquire bodhichitta, then all
your projects will be
successful, for example, people will appear who
will want to build a university for you in
Kyoto and
will pay for it, things will simply happen,
projects will begin,
goals will be achieved, and  It
says here that you won't have to strain yourself that much,
people will just show up and so
on. I
wonder if I can tell you this
story. I guess
that's
called bragging. Patthar Mia,
I'm an expert in this. I tried to find money
for our two new translators.
These guys are a mix of nationalities. They're translators. A lot of
money goes to them because
they keep
having children. So, I...  But two
salaries for my two new
translators is quite a large
sum and I thought and I don’t know how I’m going to
do
this well I just decided
to try two of my friends recently
bought Teslas to Stanley
and I complained to
you like this
get into this car this car
drives really fast down the street and all sorts of wow
I say these two friends they have a Tesla I’m
stuck in this old Toyota and
no several people who listened to this
video wrote to me I’ll
buy you any tomorrow tests by VIN of your
choice
tomorrow and I looked up
how much Teslas cost and the cheapest one was
157 thousand and I said this is what I need
this person said okay
fine tomorrow the money came and then I
said listen my car actually
works well can I ask you to
forward this money to this
translator and he was like okay that is what
I mean is that things just
happen
so
even if
another translator gets
pregnant I don’t even know if I can
talk about this now but for some reason this
happens all the time in my classes
I hope he’s not angry with me and so what
you want  Achievement will simply
happen, cool things will happen,
projects will happen, and
this is all a blessing of this motivation
to help all living beings in the universe,
therefore,
these three, as we have already said, in
general, you will be protected, you will be
loved, such a picture 1 1
you will enjoy like this
happy woman, nothing can, you will be in a
good mood, nothing
can, a wonderful cycle, and bad things
will happen around you, but in
fact, it will not affect you, and then
what, and then you will achieve
all the things you want, so
remember these four pictures and you
remembered this whole activity when you
meditate with your eyes closed,
remember as if the next picture he
showed was the next picture, and
these pictures they are able to trigger
the memory of these benefits of bodhichitta,
that is, four pictures for today and they
form four groups of benefits.
The first is that it is
protection and love, the second is
that it is
joy, 3 sharks,
things will simply happen to you
once and there will be money for a Tesla for
translators
after he sells to us, I am glad
bodhichitta
creates several,
they bring things
that will help you get,
now they say, okay,
I really want to get this car, is it
clear to you  What you want is a gift, it's not clear what I
want, how can I get it? And this is the
second big category, how do you
get this bodhichitta, which is so
cool because I hung it up
like a good salesman sold you
bodhichitta. There are two different methods
for achieving decline. There are two different ways to achieve chita. The
first is
Chan. I feel Sam Jones. That is, these are
the steps to develop this breakthrough.
This breakthrough, when you can walk and
jump across planets, is very cool and
it's worth working for a couple of
months to jump across
planets.
I don't like the word bodhichitta. I
like jumping across planets.
Stop at
each planet and check how the guys are doing. Do
n't worry. Yavas, Yavas, I'll take care of it.
And then jump
to the next ones. And by the way, the more
you
study emptiness, the more you know
that it's really possible. That it's
not with increasing. If the pen
comes from within you, then
jumping to
planets is an opportunity.
So, we will study ways to actually
get bodhichitta in the image itself,
and then we will have a
formal ceremony.  in order to
promise to
take the bodhisattva vow,
that is, two big sections. The first is
how you
learn to jump across planets, and the second
is a beautiful ceremony to
sign up for such a lifestyle. In general,
when you
learn how to be a bodhisattva, you
talk about these two steps, how to get
motivated, and then you plan such a
big ceremony. I remember when in New
York we studied ICQ courses and we studied the
vows for a month, and then we kept
talking to each other. Let's
make a really cool prison.
We took a hacker church and had a
ceremony there. It was very cool, and
then representatives of the Quaker church
said no more, you can't
come here anymore. We asked why we
did something wrong. It seemed like we were
trying to be
[music]
trying to be complan
component, they said, but you understand,
here the people
themselves in the neighborhood began to call this
church Buddhist, one way or another, that is, there will
be a ceremony. If you want, you
can
renew your vows again. If you want,
for example, you can't.  monastic vows
twice take but lunch and thoughts a hundred you
can constantly update them
I
so I have a picture for you here
she is just thinking about something and
sometimes
dadhichi then it can this is just a thought
I just want you to think about the whole
practice how you can get it will sound
so that you think about this about this practice
as about this picture it is not
actually an action it is a thinking
in this picture you are thinking about
I would like to get in the difference she does not
look different she does not act
differently it is a
change in
what intention you have in your life and
other people they really cannot
see it it is just a way of looking
at things
that is what this picture should remind you
of that
bodhichitta is
[music]
it is such a look it seems as if they
are looking into the future and it
looks like it has some
cool secret this is a
perfect picture for the struggle of a resident
ideal and there are two options
two paths if you want to
get bodhichitta there are two
classical paths there are two classical
methods
one is called the
7 steps method and cause and effect
this is the classical method of achieving
bodhichitta through seven steps  and the second
classical method, who can guess
[music]
exchange is
called exchanging oneself for others, but in
fact it is the uranium of the equation and exchange,
so it is translated, it means recognizing the
equal rights of all living beings, this is the
first part of the 2 methods, that is, the second
method begins with
recognizing the equal tackle of all
living beings with the belief that all living
beings have equal dreams and rights, not
only blacks, whites, and so on, not
only one country and another country, but all
living beings,
living beings, have equal rights.
Part 3 is the
famous part about exchanging oneself and others,
not always together and always has. Part 2,
people call it exchanging oneself for others,
but technically it is first equal dreams and
rights, and then exchange, equal rights, and exchange,
and exchanging oneself for others is not the same pain
as it
sounds, this famous warning
that this does not mean
putting yourself in another person's place, there is a
deeper, more
depressive meaning here, we will study,
so I have two minutes
for a minute,
I generally say that you are doing great,
so
we have already studied the 7-step method of
achieving bodhichitta through parables of
cause and
We have 6 consequences,
we start by comparing the gear, then the march,
what is this? This is the recognition that
people were your mothers, then throw in a
memory of all the good things they
did for you, then you try to
want to repay, then
love, beautiful love, and Neji, what is this, how much is
this,
sometimes they don't count, equal gear, so 0
march, this is
realizing that everyone was your mother,
remember their love, I want,
then you want to repay,
give them the best, the
sixth is the
flag itself, so now we have reached 7, and
7 is the result, 6 is the reasons, and 7 stages,
hichet, that is, we have completed all the
previous steps, and now we achieve the
result,
this is the final step, 1 of the Iftar methods, the
next lesson we will
begin with a description
of the Rinpoche jar,
2 methods, and then what, and
then we will move on to the second method of
bodhichitta, that
is, equal rights and exchange,
by the way, traditionally it is said that the
second method is more powerful, they
don't say you can start with the first
method and then add the second method, and
then this is an
impossible situation in which it is
impossible to lose, that is, it is good
to have the first method  and the second method
strengthens 1 this is the best option
variation and so good now a
break for the elderly to go
pee and so on so let's have a
good break